本影音版权属其出版、发行方，字幕制作仅供学术交流之用 请于下载后24小时内删除，并不得有公开传播或作商业盈利之行为 若有违法等相关行为，诸神字幕组恕不承担任何法律或连带责任。
翻译 koki  放 晴  La Fatalité
Really?
えー
そうだったよ
Yeah. Can you believe it?
压制 暗之亚瑟王  校对 凉YAN Lucifer 时间 Lucifer
So, tomorrow morning...
じゃぁ　それ…
Get Hamyuts Meseta here.
ハミュッツ＝メセタを呼べ
Who are you, sir?
どちら様でしょうか？
A monster.
怪物だ
Pl-Please wait a moment.
しょ…少々お待ち下さい
The Acting Director isn't here today.
代行は本日不在ですので
I will ask for someone else to...
今、かわりの者を…
Huh? What the hell is this?!
何事じゃ？
Todomaru mono oroka narishi
止まる者　愚かなりし
はらりひらり指に触れた黒い翼の　一片
Harari hirari yubi ni fureta
kuroi tsubasa no hitohira
诸
神字幕组
君が一つの　物語なら
Kimi ga hitotsu no monogatari nara
まだいくらでも　掛け替えられる
Mada ikura demo kakikaerareru
血のインクは乾かない
Chi no inku wa kawakanai
誰も知らない　本との僕ら
Dare mo shiranai hontou no bokura
荒れた世界　枯れるのは
Areta sekai kaeru no wa
追い求めたのは　ちっぽけな幸福なんかじゃない
Oimotometa no wa
Chippoke na koufuku nanka ja nai
戦え　轟く　音を合図に
Tatakae todoroku kodou wo aizu ni
Inomama susumeba yukusaki hatenai
意のまま　進めば
行く先　果てない
Aragae notauchi ikudo to yaburedo
抗え　のたうち
幾度と　汚れと
Kizamou matotta kizuato ni yume wo
膝を纏った傷跡に夢を
埋もれそうな今日の記憶繋げるために　明日へ
Umoresou na kyo no kioku
tsunageru tame ni ashita e
Episode 6
Thunder, a Monster, and a Girl's Punch
第6话 雷电
与
怪物
和
搏斗的少女
Oh, war-machine of the past,
the stone sword of spent time, Yor...
追憶の戦機--「過ぎ去りし石剣--夜」よ
Oh...
Hey, are you going to read it?
およ　お読みになるのですか？
I've got a fascination for monsters.
興味があるんだな　「怪物」ってやつな
Hey, Meats, we brought you some food.
ほら　「肉」ども　餌だぞ
What's the matter? Didn't snag any?
どうした？　餌を取り損ねえったか？
Look. There's a piece right here.
ほら　ここにあるぜ
いた…　この…　てめえなにしやがる　この野郎
Ow!
Jerk!
What's the matter with you?
Bastard!
Is it cold over there?
そこは…寒い　こっちに来い
Come sit by me.
It's warmer here.
こっちのほうが暖かい
I'm Relia Bookwatt.
俺はレーリア＝ブックワット　お前は？
What's your name?
Enlike Bishile.
エン…リケ＝ビスハイル
What did you do, Enlike?
エンリケは…何をした？
"Do"?
何を？
I asked for medicine.
俺は薬をもらおうとした
My friend was suffering from a fever.
仲間が　熱をだして苦しんでいたから
Why?
なぜ？
You must help others when
they're suffering.
苦しんでいたら　助けなきゃいけない
Why?
なぜ？
I don't know.
分からない
But I feel like someone did that for me.
でも　誰かがそうしてくれたような気がする
Get up.
出ろ！
U-Um, what about that girl?
あ、あの…あの子は？
She's alive and kicking.
生きてる生きてる　ぴんぴんしてる
Alive... That's great.
生きてる…
はぁー　よかった
What was that...
今の…一体？
I remember seeing it long ago...
昔見た　あれは…笑…顔
It's a smile...
A smile... He smiled.
笑顔…笑った
A smile...
笑顔
I want to smile.
笑いたい
Well? What's the experiment
for this time, old master?
で　今度は何の実験だ？　ご老体
A serum to forcibly bestow magic rights.
強制的に魔法権利を獲得させる薬だよ
An experiment.
試験…　自分死ぬ  いなくなる
I'm going to die... I'll leave this world.
ふん　飽きずによくも…
You never tire of that, do you?
I don't need you to understand.
理解してくれんで結構
Each True Man is an elevated,
isolated existence unto himself.
「真人」とはそれぞれが一つの個々　分かり合う必要なぞ…
We don't need to see eye-to-eye
on everything.
Huh?
うん？
A Meat crying?
「肉」が…泣いているだと？
Boramotte, pull him out of the cage.
ポラモット　檻から出せ
おー
Yes, sir.
ガンバルゼル
Ganbanzel...
Sit him down over here.
ここに座らせろ
You want me to sit next to a Meat?
この私に「肉」と同席しろと言うのか？
Disgusting!
不愉快だ！
Excellent. Sit right here.
ちょうどよい　ここに座れ
Why do you cry?
おぬし　なぜ泣く？
I want to smile before I die...
笑いたい…死ぬ前に…でも　できない
But I can't.
Oh, but smiling is the easiest
thing in the world!
笑うなど簡単なことではないか
You just need to do something fun.
楽しい事があればよいのだ
Fun...
楽…しい？
It means to experience the joy of living.
生きる喜びを味わうということだ
Do you know what you must do for that?
そのためにはどうすればよいか
分かるか？
Kill!
殺すことだ
Your opponent dies, and you live.
自分が生き　相手が死ぬ
生きている喜びをこれ以上に実感できることがほかにあると思うか？
Can you imagine any better means of
realizing the joy of living than this?
Killing... Fun...
殺す…楽しい…
Yes...
ああ　楽しいさ　楽しければ笑える
It's fun.
Have fun, and you'll smile.
Look at my hand.
この手を見ろ
These days, this old man's hand
couldn't kill even a child.
この年老いた手ではもはや子どもを殺すこともできん
For many years, I lived modestly
in a trading town.
長い間　わしは慎ましい一市民だった
I destroyed my desire and lied to myself.
欲望を殺し　自らに嘘をつき
By the time I realized this, it was too late.
気づいた時には　もう遅かった
だから　わしは決めたのだ
As such, I've made up my mind.
I shall create a being of superhuman
strength to act on my behalf.
わしの代わりに　最強となるものを
I shall create a monster capable of
killing Hamyuts Meseta herself!
ハミュッツ＝メセタを倒せるほどの　怪物を我が手で生み出すのだと
A monster?
怪物？
Yes. A monster!
そう　怪物だ
Minth!
ミンスさん
Stop, Minth!
止せ　ミンス
Wh-What is that?
なんだ？
An electric shock. He's projecting
electricity from his body.
電撃だ
自分の体に電気を通している  剣で触れればやられるぞ
If your sword touches him,
you'll be electrocuted!
He regenerated?
回復した？
He can use electricity, water and cloth?
雷撃使いで　水使いで　布使い？
How many magic attacks does he have?
一体いくつ魔法使えるんじゃ？
Get down, you two!
二人ども下がっていろ
I'm the only one who stands a chance.
どうやら相手になるのは俺だけだ
Highly doubtful.
お前も相手にならねえよ
We'll see about that.
それはどうだな
He can still move?
まだ動けるんのか
Milepoc! Toss me your gun!
ミレポ　銃を投げろ
He's out of bullets?
弾切れか？
Okay!
はい
Matt!
マットさん
ミンスさん
Minth!
ふん　悪いなぁ　まだ一発残ってた
Sorry. I still had a shot left.
Get back here, you jerk!
待ったん　この
Minth!
ミンスさん
You all right, Minth?
大丈夫か？　ミンス
Y-You were able to see all of that?
全部　見えとったのか？
Who knows...
さぁ　どうかな
食えん男だなぁ
Sneaky bastard.
Milepoc, inform the guards.
ミレポ　警備に連絡しろ
Tell them that if they see a masked man,
to let him through unopposed.
仮面の男が来たら　抵抗せずに通せと
We're just letting him escape?
このまま逃がするですか？
We can't stop him with our powers alone.
俺たちの力だけでは　奴を止められん
He was from the Church, wasn't he?
やはり神溺教団でしょうか？
If there's anyone else who'd
attack the Library,
彼らのほかに図書館を襲うなんて考える人がいるなら
I'd like to meet them.
会ってみたいものだわ
Do you think it's connected with
the theft of Luimon's Book?
ルイモンさんの「本」が奪われたことと何か関係が？
Who knows... But...
さぁ…
でも　これで終わりということはなさそうね
I don't think that's the last
we've seen of him.
Man, who was that guy?
なぁ　あいつは一体なんなんじゃ？
The Magic Bureau only bestows the right
to one type of magic per person.
一人の人間が魔術審議で得られる魔法権利は一つ
いくつも覚えようとすれば混沌に近寄り　心を病んでしまう
Trying to learn more would lead
only to chaos and a sick mind.
And yet...
なのに…
Look at this.
これを見ろ
Huh?
It looks like glass.
ガラスのようじゃな
It was left behind.
現場に落ちていた　多分奴の髪の毛だろう
It's probably his hair.
Translucent hair...
透明の髪の毛…まさか  それで　そのこと代行には？
It can't be! Did you tell the Acting Director?
Yeah... She ordered a unit
to pursue the monster,
それがな…　怪物の追跡を命じた後　いなくなっちまったな
and then she left.
Huh?!
はぁ？
What's going through that woman's mind?
こんなときに一体何を考えとるんじゃ
Seriously... She never makes our lives easy.
まったく　困ったお嬢さんだ
Wait!
待って
待って待って待って待ってー
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
あっ　いた
There he is.
I'm not letting you get away.
逃がさないんだから
お婆さんのかばんを返してください
Give me back the old woman's purse.
O-Out of my way!
そ、そこを退け　退かないと容赦しないぞ
If you don't move, there's
no telling what I'll do!
If you return it now, I'll recommend
leniency to the police.
今返してくれたら
重い罪にならないように  保安官さんにお願いしますから
Shut up!
うるさい
Are you having money problems?
お金に困ってるんですか？　だったら相談に乗ります
If you are, tell me and let's talk!
あたしもあまり持ってませんけど
I don't have much money myself, but...
Shut up and move. Move!
うるさい　退け　退け
返してくれないと　殴りますよ
Hand it over, or I'll punch you.
殴りたくないんです
I'd rather not have to.
Please return it at once!
早く返してください
Yes, right there!
あっ　あそこです
保安官さん
Officers, that man stole my purse.
あの男が私のかばんを
おーあ　武装司書さん
Huh? An Armed Librarian?
Thank you so much.
ありがとうございます
Take care now!
気をつけてくださいね
That was quite commendable,
Ms. Armed Librarian.
お手柄でしたね　武装司書さん
Impressive work, Ms. Armed Librarian.
さすがです　武装司書さん
Stealing from the elderly...
お年寄りを狙うなんて
You shoulda beaten the crap out of him.
あんな男を　やっつけてしまえばよかったのに
Yeah, but I thought he may have
had a good reason for it.
でも　何か事情があったのかもしれませんし
Also, I'm really not a fan
of punching people.
それにあたし　人を殴るの好きじゃないんですよね
武装司書なのに？
But you're an Armed Librarian...
Oh! Actually, I'm not an Armed Librarian.
あっ　それから　あたし武装司書じゃありません
Huh?
え？
I'm just an apprentice.
まだ　見習いです
はぁ　見習いかぁ
An apprentice, huh?
The road to becoming an Armed
Librarian is long...
武装司書への道は遠いなぁ
There she is.
いた　ノロティー　あれ？
Noloty!
Huh?
Yoo-hoo! Noloty!
あーい　ノロティー
A-Acting Director?!
代行
Hi.
はーい
Um, what are you doing here?
あのう　どうしてこんなところに？
Aren't you going to explain
how you ended up here?
じゃぁ　状況を簡単に説明してくれる？
Huh?
あっ？
Your mission was to recover
Luimon's Book, was it not?
君の任務はルイモンの「本」の奪還だたわね
Oh... Yes!
あっ　はい
He was your drill instructor, right?
確か　君の訓練教官だっけ？
はい
Yes.
And?
それで
They found Luimon's Book
in the Toatt Mine,
トアット鉱山で発見されたルイモンさんの「本」は
and it was brought here,
to Bujuia, by train.
このブジュイまで汽車で運ばれて
From here, it was to be transported
to the Library by boat.
そして船で図書館に送られるはずでした
But...
それが…
The train was attacked, and
the Book was stolen.
汽車は襲われ　「本」は奪われてしまいました
I doubt there are many with enough
power to attack a moving train.
走行中の汽車を襲えるほどの能力を持つものが  そういるとは思えません
I began my investigation with the
local criminal organizations,
周辺の犯罪組織を中心に当たっているのですが
but I've yet to uncover anything.
まだ　なにも…
Interesting...
面白いわね
Huh? What is?
あっ　なにがですか？
Oh, sorry, sorry. It's nothing.
あー　御免御免　なんでもないわよ
But anyway, why are you here?
それにしても　本当にどうしてここに？
I heard from Milepoc that
the Library was attacked.
図書館が襲われたって　ミレボックさんから聞きました
Shouldn't you be leading the
search for the monster?
怪物の捜索を指揮しているんじゃなかったんですか？
Oh, Milepoc and Ireia are more than
capable of leading the search.
指揮なら　ミレポやイレイアお婆ちゃんがいるからねえ
大丈夫よ
But she said it looked like
the Church's doing...
でも神溺教団のしわざらしいって
Ooh, a fight!
やってる　やってる
Huh?
あ？　ちょ、ちょっと
H-Hey!
What? It's glowing!
なに？　輝いてる　きれいな髪
Such beautiful hair...
"Come and punch me, for a fee
of 100 kiluwes per minute."
殴られ屋　参加料一本百キルエ
"Beat me and win 10,000 kiluwes."
殴り倒せたら一万キルエ
Don't you like these types of things?
こういうの嫌い？
Well, it's scary.
だって　怖いじゃないですか？
What are you talking about?
You're stronger than everyone there.
なに言ってるの？
ここにいる全員より強いくせに
I'm still scared.
それでも怖いんです
What if someone gets hurt?
誰かが傷ついたり　誰かを傷つけたり
What if I hurt someone?
そんなの…
ふんー　変な子
Strange girl.
Can you tell what's going on, Noloty?
分かる？　ノロティ
Oh, yes!
あっ　はい
The one taking the punches is stronger.
殴られている人の方が強いです
For some reason, he's deliberately taking
the blows and pretending they hurt.
わざと拳を受けて　効いているふりをしていますが
Time's up! That was one minute.
時間切れ　一分経ったぞ
Stay home next time, idiot!
ほら　お前ー　引っ込め
はぁー　終わりましたね
It's over!
Who's next?
次誰かいねえか？
Right here!
はーい
Huh? A-Acting Director?
だ、代行？
This girl will fight next!
次　この子が行きまーす
Huh?
はぁ？
This isn't good...
まいたなぁ
Could she be testing me?
ひょっとして　試されてる
Um, I know I look like a little girl,
but I'm an apprentice Armed Librarian,
あの　あたし…
実はこう見えても武装司書の見習いでして
so I shouldn't be doing this...
こういうことに参加のは…
Begin.
始め
I-I'm asking you not to begin!
始めないでくださいって
What should I do?
どうしよう？
Punch him! Come on!
さっさとやれ
引っ込め
Noloty! If you don't take this seriously,
you'll stay an apprentice forever.
ノロティ
ちゃーんとしないと一生見習いよ
あー　もう…
Huh?
あれ？
One punch? That's it?
もう　打たないのか？
次は　本気で行かせてもらいます
I'll hit you for real now.
Here I go!
行きます
No way.
嘘？
You gonna continue?
続けるか？
Awesome!
すごーい　すごいすごいすごい
Awesome! Awesome! Just awesome!
Will you protect the world with me?
一緒に世界を守ってくれませんか？
What are you talking about?
何を言っている？
You could definitely make
it as an Armed Librarian!
あなたなら　武装司書になれます
Let's save everyone who's
in trouble or suffering...
一緒に困っている人や苦しんでいる人
No, let's save everyone
who can be saved!
ううん　助けられる人みーんなを助けましょう
Save?
助ける？
Acting Director, this man is strong!
代行　この人強いです
Acting Director?
代行？
I'm going back.
帰るわよ
Huh?
H-Hey, wait.
あっ？　ちょっ…待っ…
Excuse me. I'll come back later.
失礼します　また来ます　考えて置いてください
Please think about it.
Why does he expend all
his strength doing that?
あんなに強いのに　あんなことしてるなんて　もったいないなぁ
What a waste...
Noloty.
ノロティ　教えることが一つあって
I have something I want to tell you.
After that, I have orders for you.
その後命令が一つあるわ
Okay...
はー？
First, I'll tell you that man's name.
It's Zatoh Rondohoon.
まずは教える事　あの男の名前はザトウ＝ロンドホーン
He's the one who stole Luimon's Book.
ルイモンの「本」を奪ったのはあいつよ
Huh? Really?
あ？
本当ですか？
But how do you know that?
でも　なんでそんなこと代行が？
Not tellin'.
教えてあげない
Next, my orders.
次に命令
Now, you can't let the other
Armed Librarians know this.
これは　他の武装司書に漏らしちゃいけない
It's what's called a top-secret mission.
いわゆる極秘指令ってやつよ
Top-secret?
極秘？
Long ago, that man killed another
man and read his Book.
彼はね　かつて一人の人を殺し　その「本」を読んだの
He then began to wish for death.
そして　死ぬことを望むようになった
What are you talking about?
どういうことですか？
This is the mission. Listen carefully.
ここからが命令よ　よく聞いて
Save that man, Zatoh.
彼を　ザトウ君を助けなさい
When he's truly in peril, save him.
彼が心底困った時に彼を助けてあげなさい
Save him...
助けるって…
That's your mission.
命令はそれだけ　じゃあね
Catch ya later.
あっ　待って下さい　代行
Hold on!
Acting Director!
H-Huh?
あ、あれ？
Save him? What on Earth...
助けるって　一体…
Hamyuts Meseta.
ハミュッツ＝メセタ
Taiyo tojiru mae ni
Hikari wo nakushite
Mekurumeku arashi nara
Temaneku mae ni tobikomu
Dare mo itsuka owaru no deshou
Sono hi ga kureba
Mawaridasu mirai wo mezashite
Tada sore wa mou shirusarete ita to shitemo
Sagashidasu kizutsuku imi sae kono te ni
Jibunrashiku aru tame ni
A Smile,
The woman named Noloty Malche.
ノロティ＝マルチェという女
A Smile, a Mask,
She enters people's hearts
with wanton disregard.
人の心を土足で踏み込む
Indelible footprints.
A Smile, a Mask, and a Man with a Death Wish
笑容与面具和求死的男人
消せない足跡　言えない爪痕
Indelible footprints.
Incurable claw marks.